<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>John Potters Professional Website Blog</title>
        <link>https://johnpottergr.com/blog</link>
        <description>John Potters Professional Website Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Mintlify is Changing API Documentation]]></title>
            <link>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-20-2025-mintlify-is-changing-api-docs</link>
            <guid>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-20-2025-mintlify-is-changing-api-docs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[For years, API documentation has lived in a strange place—necessary but neglected, important but often out of sync with the product it describes. Developers need docs to build, but maintaining them has traditionally meant choosing between clunky static pages, auto-generated markdown dumps, or overengineered CMS tools that feel more like publishing software than developer platforms.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For years, API documentation has lived in a strange place—necessary but neglected, important but often out of sync with the product it describes. Developers need docs to build, but maintaining them has traditionally meant choosing between clunky static pages, auto-generated markdown dumps, or overengineered CMS tools that feel more like publishing software than developer platforms.</p>
<p>Mintlify is trying to flip that on its head, and with the introduction of <strong>Mintlify MCP (Maintainer Control Panel)</strong>, they’re making a strong case for what modern API docs should look like—and how they should be managed.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-mintlify-mcp">What Is Mintlify MCP?<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-20-2025-mintlify-is-changing-api-docs#what-is-mintlify-mcp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What Is Mintlify MCP?" title="Direct link to What Is Mintlify MCP?">​</a></h2>
<p>Mintlify MCP isn’t just a documentation editor. It’s a centralized control panel that sits on top of your existing codebase and documentation, giving you visibility, version control integration, and collaboration tools all in one place.</p>
<p>Think of it like this: if your dev team is already keeping docs close to code, MCP makes sure those docs stay accurate, up-to-date, and consistent—without pulling anyone into a separate platform. You can flag outdated endpoints, monitor what’s being used (or ignored), and get insights into how your docs are performing.</p>
<p><strong>Some standout features include:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Live feedback from users</strong> (right in the docs)</li>
<li><strong>GitHub-native change management</strong> (suggest edits, review in PRs)</li>
<li><strong>Versioned docs tied to deployments</strong></li>
<li><strong>Analytics on engagement and usage</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>It's API documentation with an actual feedback loop—something most dev teams haven’t had before.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-this-matters">Why this matters<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-20-2025-mintlify-is-changing-api-docs#why-this-matters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why this matters" title="Direct link to Why this matters">​</a></h2>
<p>API documentation often becomes stale the moment it’s written. Products move fast. Endpoints change. Teams ship new features weekly. Unless you have a dedicated tech writer or a very disciplined team, your docs are probably wrong somewhere—and no one wants to be the engineer who stops coding to update docs.</p>
<p>Mintlify MCP brings automation and accountability into the process. It treats docs like code (with diffs, versioning, and reviews), while also giving maintainers tools to monitor what actually gets read and where people get stuck. That turns documentation from a static reference into a living part of the development cycle.</p>
<p>For API-first products and fast-growing dev tools, this can be a serious unlock. Clean, accurate, and well-managed docs aren’t just nicer—they reduce support tickets, shorten onboarding time, and build trust with external devs.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="docs-are-no-longer-an-afterthought">Docs are no longer an afterthought<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-20-2025-mintlify-is-changing-api-docs#docs-are-no-longer-an-afterthought" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Docs are no longer an afterthought" title="Direct link to Docs are no longer an afterthought">​</a></h2>
<p>The rise of tools like Mintlify MCP is part of a bigger shift: documentation is becoming infrastructure. It’s not just something you publish once—it’s something you maintain like a product. And if your product <em>is</em> an API, then the docs are the front door.</p>
<p>With the Maintainer Control Panel, Mintlify is pushing for a future where dev teams aren’t just writing better documentation—they’re actually empowered to keep it alive.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Tech Powering SaucerSwap]]></title>
            <link>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-10-2025-the-tech-powering</link>
            <guid>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-10-2025-the-tech-powering</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[If you’ve ever wondered what’s going on under the hood of SaucerSwap, here’s the quick version: it’s a decentralized exchange (DEX) built on Hedera—and that choice isn’t just for show. Hedera runs on a technology called Hashgraph, which flips the script on how most blockchains work. The difference has real consequences for how fast, cheap, and reliable a platform like SaucerSwap can be.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve ever wondered what’s going on under the hood of SaucerSwap, here’s the quick version: it’s a decentralized exchange (DEX) built on Hedera—and that choice isn’t just for show. Hedera runs on a technology called Hashgraph, which flips the script on how most blockchains work. The difference has real consequences for how fast, cheap, and reliable a platform like SaucerSwap can be.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="not-built-on-blockchain">Not built on blockchain<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-10-2025-the-tech-powering#not-built-on-blockchain" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Not built on blockchain" title="Direct link to Not built on blockchain">​</a></h2>
<p>Let’s back up for a second. Most DEXs reside on Ethereum or similar chains. That means they rely on traditional blockchain architecture: a chain of blocks, added one after the other, with each block holding a bunch of transactions. It’s a tried-and-true system, but it has its limits, with network congestion, high fees, and latency being the big ones.</p>
<p>Hedera’s Hashgraph works differently. Instead of blocks, it uses a <a href="https://hazelcast.com/foundations/distributed-computing/directed-acyclic-graph/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">directed acyclic graph (DAG)</a>—a data structure where transactions aren’t stacked linearly, but spread out and recorded in parallel. Techies use a <a href="https://docs.hedera.com/hedera/core-concepts/hashgraph-consensus-algorithms/gossip-about-gossip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gossip-about-gossip protocol</a> here, which means every node quickly shares info with random others. Over time, the whole network has a complete picture of what happened and when, with no mining, leader, or lag.</p>
<img src="https://johnpottergr.com/img/hashgraph.jpg" width="600">
<p>The way Hashgraph handles consensus is key. Every transaction comes with a timestamp, and the network uses a virtual voting mechanism to agree on the order of events. That’s how it moves so fast—thousands of transactions per second, and everything settles in seconds instead of minutes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="real-time-settlement-low-fees">Real-time settlement, low fees<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-10-2025-the-tech-powering#real-time-settlement-low-fees" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Real-time settlement, low fees" title="Direct link to Real-time settlement, low fees">​</a></h2>
<p>For a DEX like SaucerSwap, the Hashgraph technology makes a big difference. Trades get confirmed almost instantly. While <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/slippage.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">slippage</a> is still largely a factor of liquidity and trading volume, it's much lower. And it's practically impossible for bots to exploit transaction delay windows. The entire trading experience feels snappier and more predictable, even when the market’s moving fast.</p>
<p>The tech also leads to lower costs. Because no miners compete for block space, gas fees on SaucerSwap are low and predictable. Think in terms of fractions of a cent. The hashgraph tech opens the door for microtransactions and lower-volume activity that would be priced out on other platforms. You don’t have to think twice about trying a swap just to see how a token behaves. And all fees are fixed and denominated in USD-equivalent HBAR.</p>
<p>Predictable performance is another upside. Since Hashgraph isn’t battling network congestion in the same way as other chains, you don’t get stuck waiting for a transaction to go through during peak times. The throughput is consistent, and that predictability is worth a lot in a trading environment.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="native-token-support-via-hts">Native token support via HTS<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-10-2025-the-tech-powering#native-token-support-via-hts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Native token support via HTS" title="Direct link to Native token support via HTS">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap is tightly integrated with <a href="https://hedera.com/token-service" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedera Token Service (HTS)</a>, which handles the basics—creating tokens, transferring them, freezing or wiping them—without the need for smart contracts. It’s native, fast, and cheap. So, for most token operations, SaucerSwap can skip the overhead of smart contracts and rely on HTS to do the heavy lifting.</p>
<p>But when it comes to more complex functionality—things like routing trades across multiple pools, setting custom logic for incentives, or interacting with other DeFi protocols—SaucerSwap taps into Hedera’s Smart Contract Service. This service is EVM-compatible, meaning developers can write in Solidity and build the kinds of applications they’re used to building on Ethereum.</p>
<p>The difference is that those smart contracts run on Hedera’s Hashgraph under the hood, so you still get low fees and high throughput.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-10-2025-the-tech-powering#final-thoughts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final thoughts" title="Direct link to Final thoughts">​</a></h2>
<p>The entire SaucerSwap setup helps make operations smooth for users and developers. Less friction, fewer surprises. It’s not out to reinvent DeFi, but it shows what DeFi can look like when you build it on something faster and more scalable right from the start.</p>
<p>So while you could use SaucerSwap without knowing a thing about DAGs, Hashgraph, or the rest of the tech stack, understanding what powers the DEX helps explain why it runs the way it does. Building something yourself on the DEX might make you rethink what kind of infrastructure you want under your project.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 5 Use Cases for Saucerswap]]></title>
            <link>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases</link>
            <guid>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[While most platforms are still chasing faster, cheaper crypto trading, SaucerSwap’s already delivering. As Hedera’s main DEX, it’s gaining real traction—with over $130 million in total value locked as of early 2025. But it’s not just about token swaps anymore. Traders are using it for staking, governance, liquidity rewards—practical features that are actually getting used.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While most platforms are still chasing faster, cheaper crypto trading, <a href="https://www.saucerswap.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaucerSwap</a>’s already delivering. As Hedera’s main DEX, it’s gaining real traction—with over $130 million in total value locked as of early 2025. But it’s not just about token swaps anymore. Traders are using it for staking, governance, liquidity rewards—practical features that are actually getting used.</p>
<p>If you’ve been wondering why SaucerSwap keeps popping up in DeFi circles, these five use cases make it clear: it’s not just hype.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1-seamless-token-swaps">1: Seamless Token Swaps<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases#1-seamless-token-swaps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1: Seamless Token Swaps" title="Direct link to 1: Seamless Token Swaps">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap does one thing really well: fast, reliable token swaps. It taps into the <a href="https://hedera.com/token-service" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedera Token Service (HTS)</a>, which means trades settle in about 3 to 5 seconds—no waiting or surprise gas fees. SaucerSwap also prices transaction costs in USD, which keeps fees low and predictable. That’s a big plus for high-volume traders and anyone fed up with Ethereum’s delays and costs.</p>
<p>Swapping HBAR for USDC or newer HTS tokens feels smooth, and with SaucerSwap V2’s concentrated liquidity, slippage stays low—even in smaller pools. The smoother experience is helping SaucerSwap pull users away from <a href="https://uniswap.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Uniswap</a> and other Ethereum-based DEXs.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2-liquidity-provision-and-yield-farming">2: Liquidity Provision and Yield Farming<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases#2-liquidity-provision-and-yield-farming" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2: Liquidity Provision and Yield Farming" title="Direct link to 2: Liquidity Provision and Yield Farming">​</a></h2>
<p>The process to provide liquidity on SaucerSwap is simple: pick a token pair, deposit both tokens into a pool, and get LP tokens in return. In return, you earn 0.25% of every swap made in that pool. It’s passive, steady, and a big draw for yield-focused users.</p>
<p>SaucerSwap has raised the bar with its Liquidity-Aligned Reward Initiative, or LARI. The program offers dual rewards—HBAR and SAUCE—for users who provide liquidity in its V2 concentrated liquidity pools. Instead of traditional LP tokens, your position is represented by an NFT. That NFT can then be staked using the Masterchef contract, allowing you to earn fees and rewards while your liquidity stays active in the pool.</p>
<p>The desire for passive income has attracted long-term investors looking beyond quick gains. It has also added real depth and stability to SaucerSwap’s liquidity. The result is a trading platform where traders can park their assets and earn over time. Growing user commitment is turning it into a central hub for DeFi activity on <a href="https://hedera.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedera</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="3-governance-via-sauce-token">3: Governance via SAUCE Token<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases#3-governance-via-sauce-token" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 3: Governance via SAUCE Token" title="Direct link to 3: Governance via SAUCE Token">​</a></h2>
<p>The SAUCE token does more than reward users—it opens the door to governance. As SaucerSwap’s decision-making tool, SAUCE gives holders the ability to vote on key protocol updates, including fee structures, liquidity incentives, and reward mechanisms. In 2025, the DAO continues to expand its role, with potential votes on cross-chain integrations like <a href="https://axelar.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Axelar</a> outlined in recent roadmaps.</p>
<p>Governance appeals to users who care about decentralization and want a say in how platforms evolve. As participation grows, SaucerSwap moves further from a top-down model. Community-driven decision-making makes everyday users active stakeholders, giving SaucerSwap an edge no centralized exchange can match—real ownership.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="4-cross-chain-liquidity-hub">4: Cross-Chain Liquidity Hub<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases#4-cross-chain-liquidity-hub" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 4: Cross-Chain Liquidity Hub" title="Direct link to 4: Cross-Chain Liquidity Hub">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap’s plans to integrate with bridge protocols like <a href="https://axelar.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Axelar</a> and <a href="https://layerzero.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LayerZero</a> will enable seamless asset transfers across chains. In a multi-chain DeFi environment, this partnership helps Hedera connect with ecosystems like Ethereum, Solana, and Avalanche.</p>
<p>Imagine swapping wrapped BTC from Ethereum directly for HBAR via SaucerSwap at Hedera speeds. The move heralds a major step toward frictionless liquidity. As more users look for efficient, low-fee ways to move assets between chains, SaucerSwap’s cross-chain functionality could make it a go-to hub. It’s bound to lead to a broader user base, deeper liquidity pools, and a more competitive position in the DeFi space.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="5-community-pool-token-launches">5: Community Pool Token Launches<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases#5-community-pool-token-launches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 5: Community Pool Token Launches" title="Direct link to 5: Community Pool Token Launches">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap’s community pools introduce a new way to launch tokens—placing distribution directly in user hands rather than under centralized control. Unlike a traditional launchpad, this model lets new projects build liquidity pools that directly reward early supporters.</p>
<p>Community pools continue to gain traction, with token launches tied to staking xSAUCE or holding ecosystem NFTs such as SAUCELINGs. For example, a new DeFi project might distribute tokens to xSAUCE stakers and offer bonus multipliers to SAUCELING holders. The system rewards participants without relying on gatekeepers.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="wrapping-it-up">Wrapping It Up<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/4-02-2025-top-5-use-cases#wrapping-it-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Wrapping It Up" title="Direct link to Wrapping It Up">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap has come a long way. Token swaps are smooth. Yield farming feels accessible. Governance works. New projects are launching with real community support. Now, with cross-chain growth on the horizon, it’s starting to feel like more than a DEX. Hedera’s speed and low fees give it a competitive edge, but what really stands out is how involved users have become. If you're interested, try staking SAUCE or checking out a pool launch. Even a single vote in the DAO can show you what this kind of platform is building toward.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why SaucerSwap's Quietly Winning in DeFi]]></title>
            <link>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning</link>
            <guid>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Using a DEX can feel way harder than it needs to be. One minute you’re making a basic swap. The next, gas fees eat half your gains, your transaction gets front-run, and you're stuck navigating a UI that looks like it hasn’t been updated since 2015. It's enough to make you wonder if DeFi's worth the hassle.  That’s usually when someone drops, “Have you looked at SaucerSwap?” Usually followed by, “Wait—the one on Hedera? The chain with SWIFT on the council?”]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Using a DEX can feel way harder than it needs to be. One minute you’re making a basic swap. The next, gas fees eat half your gains, your transaction gets front-run, and you're stuck navigating a UI that looks like it hasn’t been updated since 2015. It's enough to make you wonder if DeFi's worth the hassle.  That’s usually when someone drops, “Have you looked at <a href="https://www.saucerswap.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaucerSwap</a>?” Usually followed by, “Wait—the one on <a href="https://hedera.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedera</a>? The chain with <a href="https://www.swift.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SWIFT</a> on the council?”</p>
<p>SaucerSwap isn’t trying to reinvent the wheel. It’s just quietly building a faster, cleaner, less painful way to trade—staking, farming, and all. And if you’re tired of friction every time you try to move a few tokens, it might be worth a look. Let’s explore what makes SaucerSwap different—and why it could be one of the more interesting DEXs to watch.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hedera-power-the-secret-behind-saucerswap">Hedera Power: The Secret Behind SaucerSwap<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#hedera-power-the-secret-behind-saucerswap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hedera Power: The Secret Behind SaucerSwap" title="Direct link to Hedera Power: The Secret Behind SaucerSwap">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap doesn’t play by the usual DeFi rules. It’s built on <a href="https://hedera.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedera</a>—a network that takes a different approach to speed and cost. Unlike traditional blockchain tech, Hedera uses a system called hashgraph, which handles thousands of transactions per second and keeps fees at about a penny or less. Compare that to <a href="https://ethereum.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ethereum</a>, where gas fees can spike unexpectedly and drain your wallet fast. If you’re looking to swap tokens or earn yield without burning cash, SaucerSwap’s low-cost efficiency is a smart choice.</p>
<p>Hedera also brings some credibility to the table. The council that governs Hedera includes prominent names like <a href="https://www.google.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google</a>, <a href="https://www.ibm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM</a>, and <a href="https://www.swift.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SWIFT</a>—the same SWIFT that powers much of the global banking system. That’s not hype; institutional backing sets it apart from many other blockchain platforms.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="smooth-no-nonsense-swaps">Smooth, No-Nonsense Swaps<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#smooth-no-nonsense-swaps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Smooth, No-Nonsense Swaps" title="Direct link to Smooth, No-Nonsense Swaps">​</a></h2>
<p>At its core, SaucerSwap helps you conduct token swaps. It’s a decentralized exchange (DEX), which means you’re trading directly from your wallet—no intermediaries get in the way. But what makes it stand out is how seamless the experience is. Hedera’s high throughput and low latency mean swaps typically settle in seconds, so you can execute trades fast—no waiting around.</p>
<p>You don’t have to wait for block confirmations, and your transaction won’t get held up behind others in a queue. If you’ve ever had a trade hijacked by front-running bots—those automated programs that jump ahead of your order—Hedera's structure blocks that from happening. Rather than rely on a mempool, which can expose transactions before they finalize, Hedera processes trades in a way that prevents those tactics entirely. The result is a faster, more predictable trading experience—especially for anyone frustrated by the congestion common to Ethereum-based platforms.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="staking-and-farming-simplified">Staking and Farming, Simplified<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#staking-and-farming-simplified" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Staking and Farming, Simplified" title="Direct link to Staking and Farming, Simplified">​</a></h2>
<p>Beyond token swaps, SaucerSwap makes staking and yield farming easy to navigate. You can stake your SAUCE tokens in just a few clicks and start earning rewards—no complex setup or deep crypto knowledge needed. The platform also stakes all HBAR in its liquidity pools directly on the Hedera network, earning additional rewards that it converts to SAUCE and shares with stakers. It’s passive income on autopilot: set it, forget it, and watch your holdings grow.</p>
<p>Yield farming gives you a bit more flexibility. Pair tokens, add them to liquidity pools, and earn both trading fees and SAUCE rewards. The interface is clean and intuitive—no clutter, no confusing menus, and nothing sketchy. It’s a set-it-and-forget-it setup that lets your holdings grow over time.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="transparent-fees-that-stay-low">Transparent Fees That Stay Low<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#transparent-fees-that-stay-low" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Transparent Fees That Stay Low" title="Direct link to Transparent Fees That Stay Low">​</a></h2>
<p>Nobody likes watching fees chip away at gains. SaucerSwap keeps transaction costs predictable thanks to Hedera’s fixed, USD-based fee structure. You know exactly what you’ll pay before you hit confirm—no surprises.</p>
<p>During periods of high network activity, Ethereum gas fees can spike dramatically, making trades on other DEXs more expensive. SaucerSwap avoids this problem entirely by offering low fees that stay around a fraction of a cent. If you’re a frequent trader or work with smaller positions, you can trade confidently, knowing costs won’t chip away at your gains.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="feature-comparison-table">Feature Comparison Table<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#feature-comparison-table" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Feature Comparison Table" title="Direct link to Feature Comparison Table">​</a></h3>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-saucerswaps-building-behind-the-scenes">What SaucerSwap’s Building Behind the Scenes<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#what-saucerswaps-building-behind-the-scenes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What SaucerSwap’s Building Behind the Scenes" title="Direct link to What SaucerSwap’s Building Behind the Scenes">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap isn’t standing still. While most DEXs are busy chasing hype, it's steadily building out features that make trading smarter and more accessible. Here’s a look at what’s new and coming down the pipeline—and why it matters.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="smarter-trading-tools-for-real-traders">Smarter Trading Tools for Real Traders<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#smarter-trading-tools-for-real-traders" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Smarter Trading Tools for Real Traders" title="Direct link to Smarter Trading Tools for Real Traders">​</a></h3>
<p>SaucerSwap is rolling out advanced tools like on-chain limit orders and stop-loss functionality—features that let you set exact price points for trades. Its goal is to make trading more intentional, which means fewer emotional decisions and more control. Dollar-cost averaging (DCA) is also in the works, so you’ll be able to automate regular buys and take the edge off market swings. These features rarely show up in basic DEXs—but SaucerSwap’s baking them in for users who want more control.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cross-chain-ready">Cross-Chain Ready<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#cross-chain-ready" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cross-Chain Ready" title="Direct link to Cross-Chain Ready">​</a></h3>
<p>Cross-chain integration with <a href="https://axelar.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Axelar</a> and <a href="https://layerzero.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LayerZero</a> means SaucerSwap isn’t limited to Hedera. You’ll be able to move assets between blockchains—like bringing over tokens from Ethereum—without leaving the platform. That opens the door to more liquidity, more users, and far more trading possibilities. For serious DeFi users, it also means flexibility. For institutions, it shows a platform that’s thinking ahead.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="security-that-is-actually-built-in">Security That Is Actually Built In<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#security-that-is-actually-built-in" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Security That Is Actually Built In" title="Direct link to Security That Is Actually Built In">​</a></h3>
<p>Security and compliance aren’t bolted on after the fact. SaucerSwap is integrating with tools like <a href="https://www.chainalysis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainalysis</a> and <a href="https://www.chainabuse.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainabuse</a>, as detailed in its January 2025 roadmap. This feature matters if you’re thinking long-term, especially as regulators pay more attention to crypto. With institutional-grade monitoring and transparency, the platform isn’t just trying to grow fast; it’s doing it the right way.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="wrapping-it-up">Wrapping It Up<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-31-2025-why-saucerswap-is-quietly-winning#wrapping-it-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Wrapping It Up" title="Direct link to Wrapping It Up">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap hits a rare combo: speed, affordability, and simplicity. It’s also built on Hedera—a blockchain with real weight behind it. The tech runs smoothly, the experience is intuitive, and with SWIFT involved, there’s a clear signal that this could scale far beyond the usual DeFi crowd. Whether you’re swapping, staking, or farming, SaucerSwap hits that rare balance between simplicity and capability. Try a few trades with HBAR and see why this DEX is quietly gaining ground in the DeFi space.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getting Started with SaucerSwap -- A Beginner's Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap</link>
            <guid>https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to SaucerSwap!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="welcome-to-saucerswap">Welcome to SaucerSwap!<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#welcome-to-saucerswap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Welcome to SaucerSwap!" title="Direct link to Welcome to SaucerSwap!">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.saucerswap.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaucerSwap</a> is a top-tier decentralized exchange (DEX) built on the <a href="https://hedera.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedera</a> network. It’s a platform where you can trade cryptocurrencies like HBAR and other Hedera Token Service (HTS) tokens quickly, securely, and with fees that won’t break the bank. Whether you’re looking to swap tokens, provide liquidity, or stake your assets, this guide will help you take your first steps. No middlemen, no hassle—just you and your crypto!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-youll-need-before-you-begin">What You’ll Need Before You Begin<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#what-youll-need-before-you-begin" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What You’ll Need Before You Begin" title="Direct link to What You’ll Need Before You Begin">​</a></h2>
<p>To get started, you’ll need a few essentials:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>A Hedera Wallet</strong>: SaucerSwap works with wallets compatible with the Hedera network, such as <a href="https://hashpack.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HashPack</a> or <a href="https://bladewallet.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Blade</a>. These wallets store your HBAR and tokens securely.</li>
<li><strong>HBAR</strong>: The native cryptocurrency of Hedera, HBAR is required to pay for transaction fees on SaucerSwap. You can purchase HBAR on exchanges like <a href="https://www.binance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Binance</a>, <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Coinbase</a>, or <a href="https://www.kucoin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KuCoin</a> and transfer it to your wallet.<br>
<!-- -->Alternatively, SaucerSwap offers a Coinbase Onramp, allowing you to buy and transfer HBAR directly within the platform. Simply navigate to the <em>Swap</em> page and select the <em>Buy</em> tab next to <em>Swap</em> to get started.</li>
<li><strong>A Web Browser</strong>: Access SaucerSwap through a browser like <a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chrome</a> or <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Firefox</a> by visiting <a href="https://www.saucerswap.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.saucerswap.finance/</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1-set-up-your-hedera-wallet">Step 1: Set Up Your Hedera Wallet<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#step-1-set-up-your-hedera-wallet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 1: Set Up Your Hedera Wallet" title="Direct link to Step 1: Set Up Your Hedera Wallet">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Download a Wallet</strong>: Visit <a href="https://hashpack.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://hashpack.app/</a> (for HashPack) or <a href="https://bladewallet.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://bladewallet.io/</a> (for Blade) and follow the instructions to install the wallet as a browser extension or mobile app.</li>
<li><strong>Create Your Wallet</strong>: Open the app, click “Create Wallet,” and follow the prompts. You’ll get a seed phrase—a 12- or 24-word sequence. Write it down and store it somewhere safe (never share it!).</li>
<li><strong>Add HBAR</strong>: Send HBAR from an exchange to your wallet’s Hedera account ID (looks like <code>0.0.xxxxxx</code>)—grab it from your wallet app. Double-check the address, as mistakes are permanent. Expect it to arrive in minutes!</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2-connect-to-saucerswap">Step 2: Connect to SaucerSwap<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#step-2-connect-to-saucerswap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2: Connect to SaucerSwap" title="Direct link to Step 2: Connect to SaucerSwap">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Visit the Site</strong>: Go to <a href="https://www.saucerswap.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.saucerswap.finance/</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Connect Your Wallet</strong>: Click “Connect Wallet” in the top-right corner. Select your wallet (e.g., HashPack or Blade) from the options. Approve the connection in your wallet app when prompted.</li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A wallet screen" src="https://johnpottergr.com/assets/images/connect-your-wallet-c3ac63ba0168f03bb81ce4ee8eb9ec69.jpg" width="1534" height="946" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Verify Connection</strong>: Once connected, you’ll see your wallet’s HBAR balance displayed on the SaucerSwap interface.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-3-start-swapping-tokens">Step 3: Start Swapping Tokens<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#step-3-start-swapping-tokens" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 3: Start Swapping Tokens" title="Direct link to Step 3: Start Swapping Tokens">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Navigate to Swap</strong>: On the homepage, find the “Swap” section (it’s front and center!).</li>
<li><strong>Choose Tokens</strong>: Select the token you want to swap from (e.g., HBAR) and the token you want to receive (e.g., SAUCE or USDC). If you don’t see a token, you may need to add it manually using its token ID (available on Hedera explorers like <a href="https://hashscan.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HashScan</a>).</li>
<li><strong>Enter Amount</strong>: Input how much you want to swap. SaucerSwap will calculate the amount you’ll receive, factoring in a small fee (denominated in USD, paid in HBAR).</li>
<li><strong>Adjust Slippage (Optional)</strong>: Click the gear icon to tweak slippage tolerance (e.g., 0.5%) if you’re worried about price changes during the transaction—it’s the max price shift you’ll accept to protect against losses from market moves. For volatile tokens, bump it to 1–3%.</li>
<li><strong>Swap It</strong>: Click “Swap,” review the details, and confirm the transaction in your wallet. In seconds, your new tokens will appear!</li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A swap-it screen" src="https://johnpottergr.com/assets/images/swap-it-1fa6aa8c7840ad848b7d8235596a34a2.jpg" width="1060" height="1232" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-4-explore-more-features">Step 4: Explore More Features<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#step-4-explore-more-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 4: Explore More Features" title="Direct link to Step 4: Explore More Features">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Add Liquidity</strong>: If you want to earn fees, go to the “Liquidity” tab, pick a token pair (e.g., HBAR/USDC), and supply equal values of both tokens to a pool. You’ll get LP tokens representing your share—think of them as a receipt. These earn a cut of trading fees (check the pool’s APR on the site), which you can claim later by removing liquidity.</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A add liquidity screen" src="https://johnpottergr.com/assets/images/add-liquidity-b935ca5e8b6de6fcc8e78244cc8b4fa7.jpg" width="2286" height="706" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Stake SAUCE</strong>: If you own SAUCE tokens, you can stake them to earn rewards. Head to the “Stake” section, deposit them into the Infinity Pool, and earn xSAUCE, which grows in value over time as a reward.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A stake SAUCE screen" src="https://johnpottergr.com/assets/images/stake-sauce-f5436b7b676a5ba873efb25887edb82d.jpg" width="1224" height="1012" class="img_ev3q"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Check Your Progress</strong>: Use Hedera explorers like <a href="https://hashscan.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://hashscan.io/</a> to track your transactions and balances.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="tips-for-beginners">Tips for Beginners<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#tips-for-beginners" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Tips for Beginners" title="Direct link to Tips for Beginners">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Start Small</strong>: Test with a small amount of HBAR or tokens to get comfortable.</li>
<li><strong>Watch Fees</strong>: SaucerSwap fees are low and in USD (paid in HBAR), but ensure you have enough HBAR for transactions.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Safe</strong>: Never share your seed phrase or private keys. SaucerSwap is self-custody, meaning you control your assets—no one else.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="troubleshooting">Troubleshooting<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#troubleshooting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Troubleshooting" title="Direct link to Troubleshooting">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stuck?</strong> If a swap fails, check your HBAR balance for fees (a few cents usually does it).</li>
<li><strong>Wallet not connecting?</strong> Refresh the page or reinstall the extension.</li>
<li><strong>Still lost?</strong> Hit up the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/saucerswap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>! Or visit our <a href="https://docs.saucerswap.finance/tutorials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tutorials page</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-saucerswap">Why SaucerSwap?<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#why-saucerswap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why SaucerSwap?" title="Direct link to Why SaucerSwap?">​</a></h2>
<p>SaucerSwap stands out with Hedera’s fast transaction speeds, fair pricing (no MEV attacks like on Ethereum), and a user-friendly design. Whether you’re trading, staking, or providing liquidity, it’s a secure gateway to decentralized finance (DeFi).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="need-help">Need Help?<a href="https://johnpottergr.com/blog/3-27-2025-getting-started-with-saucerswap#need-help" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Need Help?" title="Direct link to Need Help?">​</a></h2>
<p>Join the SaucerSwap community for support:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Discord</strong>: <a href="https://discord.com/invite/saucerswap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://discord.com/invite/saucerswap</a></li>
<li><strong>Twitter</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/SaucerSwapLabs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://twitter.com/SaucerSwapLabs</a></li>
<li><strong>Docs</strong>: <a href="https://docs.saucerswap.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://docs.saucerswap.finance/</a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>